Shalom Bhooshi

s.bhooshi@gmail.com o +421 948 140 290

Abstract

A software-centric systems engineer with 15 years experience and background in agile delivery of infrastructure projects in various business settings. I seek a role in a progressive organization that employs cloud and modern open-source technologies with agile and devops practices to innovate and advance business.

Core Competencies

- · Software Engineering through Infrastructure-as-Code for Infrastructure, Tooling and Automation
- · Site Reliability Engineering practices for business excellence and customer satisfaction
- · Application of Agile Methodologies and Dev(Sec|Test)Ops to realize Continuous Delivery
- · Use of Cloud-Native paradigms and technologies to engineer Service Agility and Reliability
- Solution Design and Implementation with Big Picture Thinking and Design for Iteration
- · Results-Oriented attitude using Initiative, Organization, Communication and Teamwork

Technical Skills

Cloud Platforms Canonical Openstack, Amazon ec2/AWS, Apache Cloudstack, Google Cloud Operating Systems Debian/Ubuntu/CentOS Linux, Windows Server 2003-2016, FreeBSD 9+ Scripting Languages Python, Bash/POSIX Shell, Golang, Ruby, Perl, Powershell/.NET, Raku Configuration Jinja2, ERB, YAML, JSON, JSON Schema, JSON Path, TOML, XML laC git, Github, Ansible, Terraform, Makefiles, GitOps, StackStorm Cl/CD Gitlab CI, Gitlab Runners, Travis CI, JFrog Artifactory, Jenkins Containers docker, docker-compose, Kubernetes, Consul

Containers docker, docker-compose, Nubernetes, Consul

 $\textbf{Observability} \hspace{0.2cm} \textbf{Prometheus, Grafana, Graylog2, Icinga2/CheckMK, New Relic, Airbrake, Cacting CheckMK, New Relic, Cacting CheckMK, New Cacting CheckMK, New CheckMK, New CheckMK, New CheckMK, New CheckM$

Web nginx, Apache, Cloudflare, Citrix NetScaler, Python Flask, REST, SOA

Databases Postgres 9+, MariaDB 10/MySQL 5+, Elasticsearch, CouchDB, Redis, SQLite 3

Networking TCP/IP (IPv4 & IPv6), DNS, VPC/Network Design, VPNs, L4/L7 Load-Balancing

Virtualization Citrix XenServer, KVM, Xen, Microsoft Hyper-V

Hardware Dell PowerEdge, HP Proliant, HP BladeSystem

Storage NFS, iSCSI, Swift/S3, Dell Compellent, NetApp, HP StorageWorks

Other See my StackOverflow Developer Story for assessments and opensource work.

Professional Experience

Aug 2017 → Present Deutsche Telekom Pan-Net ∘ Bratislava, Slovakia

pan-net.cloud provides a pan-european cloud platform and infrastructure services to partners and affiliates in the wider Deutsche Telekom group. Providing a platform for specialised Network Technology Services (Voice, Video & Data) and general-purpose IT/Cloud-Native workloads, Pan-Net uses best-of-breed cloud technologies to support backend laaS/PaaS/SaaS for the Deutsche Telecom product lines.

Jun 2019 → Present Technical Lead/Cloud Infrastructure Engineer, IT PaaS, Pan-Net Cloud

Skills & Experience Product/Technology Ownership, Backlog Management, Scrumban, DevOps, CI/CD/CT, Openstack, Terraform, Ansible, Gitlab, Golang, Python, Prometheus

- As a Technical Lead: Working closely with Product Owners and peers across units Agile product roadmap alignment, breakdown of business requirements into user/job stories in product backlogs, technical solution research & development, sprint scheduling, solution reviews.
- As an Infrastructure Engineer: Participating in team scrums to develop, deliver and advance PaaS offerings in an
 aaS fashion to complement and enrich the Openstack IaaS (e.g. DBaaS, LBaaS, FaaS, Big Data/NoSQL, Service
 Monitoring, Log Management, Data Archival, Disaster Recovery).
- As part of the technology community: Participating in design thinking workshops, production campuses. Engaging customers & partners. Presenting technology, knowledge sharing.

Feb 2018 → May 2019 Cloud Infrastructure Engineer, NFVI CI/CD, Pan-Net NFVI

Skills & Experience Agile Release Trains, Delivery Pipelines, DevOps, Gitlab CI, Artifactory, Openstack, Docker, Ansible, Linux, Terraform, Python, goss, Prometheus, Grafana

- Member of the team tasked with the design, implementation and DevOps of distributed highly-available CI/CD/CT services (i.e. Gitlab CI/CD, Job Runners, Binary Repositories, Library Code) that sustain the IaC and Continuous Delivery activities of Pan-Net platform services.
- Supporting service delivery teams in consultation and design of CI/CD pipelines, git branching and release models, Dev(Sec|Test)Ops processes, Application Lifecycle & Orchestration.

Aug 2017 → **Jan 2018** Cloud Infrastructure Engineer, NFVI Application Orchestration, Pan-Net NFVI **Skills & Experience** Openstack, OpenContrail, Linux, Ansible, Python, OASIS TOSCA, StackStorm

- Part of team tasked with developing the Pan-Net VNF Orchestration engines and best-practices around VNF Lifecycle Management (Instantiation, Upgrades, Auto-Healing, Scale in/out, etc).
- Participating in product design workshops, scrum & sprint activities. Designing VNF orchestration solutions and automation worklows on OpenStack, CI/CD, systems testing, releases.

Oct 2015 - Jun 2017 Box+Dice (BDSK) · Bratislava, Slovakia

Box+Dice provide a SaaS/CRM platform for businesses in the Australian & New Zealand real estate sector to manage property portfolios, marketing and lead management, sales and accounting, portal integrations, etc in realtime. With 250+ businesses as clients across the Oceania region, Box+Dice harnesses in-house and customer domain expertise to deliver tailored SaaS services.

Oct 2015 → Jun 2017 Senior Systems Engineer, Site Reliability Engineering

Skills & Experience Amazon AWS, Project Planning, SRE, DevSecOps, Jira, Mentoring, Ansible, Terraform, bash, Python, Ruby, Cloudflare, Linux, Postgres, MariaDB, Elasticsearch

- Lead systems engineer managing DevOps and Site Reliability Engineering across polar opposite timezones (Bratislava/Kiev vs Melbourne/Wellington): systems analysis, infrastructure design and development, improving production deployments and platform availability.
- Delivering on projects to modernize infrastructure: *Lift-and-shift* platform to public cloud (AWS), improving cloud integration & efficiency/scalability, improving technical security and operations.
- Working on cross-functional efforts with Product Development, Quality Engineering and Product Support: Improving DevOps operating procedures, CI/CD, QA, communications.
- Involved in defining and project managing systems strategy, participating in executive committee decision making, customer technical support, cost management, hiring, mentoring.

Jul 2010 → Aug 2015 Citrix Systems UK Ltd · Cambridge, United Kingdom

Citrix solutions power business mobility through secure, mobile workspaces that provide people with instant access to apps, desktops, data and communications. With annual revenue in 2014 of \$3.14 billion, Citrix solutions are in use at more than 400,000 organizations and by over 100 million users globally.

Oct 2013 - Aug 2015 Senior Software Test Engineer, Engineering Productivity, Enterprise Desktop and Applications Skills & Experience IaaS, Cloud Architecture, Network Design, Enterprise Software Testing, DevOps, Teamwork, Mentoring, Virtualization, CloudStack, XenServer, PowerShell/.NET, Perl, Python, Ruby, Linux, Windows Server, WDS, CouchDB, Icinga, Puppet

- Systems Architect/DevOps Engineer of a self-service laaS cloud (Apache CloudStack/XenServer) supporting adhoc and Continuous Testing activities of 65+ internal engineering teams.
- Solving push-button provisioning of Citrix VDI (Virtual Desktop Infrastructure) test environments on Cloud and Virtualization Backends (Xenserver, ESX, Hyper-v, Azure), Improving QA self-service capabilities, enriching cloud offerings through automation, VM image creation/cataloguing, etc.
- · Member of the core automation team stewarding test automation frameworks and test library code underpinning QA strategies of the Citrix Desktop and App virtualization suites. Lead developer of perl components to support testing Mac and Linux/Unix end-points.
- · Refining agile practices for code and test infrastructure evolution. Setting up backend infrastructure for Citrix Summit. Hardware procurement and maintenance, vendor relations. Technical training/mentoring.

Apr 2012 - Oct 2013 Associate Software Test Engineer, Engineering Productivity, Enterprise Desktop and Applications

Jui 2010	→ Apr 2012	Software	iest Engineer,	lest Automation,	xenDesktop	∟ngineerin	ıg

от поставо на поставо
May 2007 → Dec 2007 Crystal Amusements (UK) Ltd ∘ London, United Kingdom
Systems Engineer Windows, JScript/WSH, TCP/IP Routing/Switching, Network Reliability/Security
Jan 2007 → May 2007 Sterling Limousines (UK) Ltd ∘ Richmond, Surrey, United Kingdom LAMP Developer Perl, PrototypeJS, Apache/mod perl, Postgresql, Linux, Windows Server 2003
Aug 2002 → Oct 2006 Freelance IT Engineer ∘ Greater London Area, United Kingdom

IT Contractor Office LAN Design, Web Design & Mastering, Linux, Windows Workstation/Server, Microsoft Office, TCP/IP Routing/Switching, Apache/IIS, Perl, VBScript/Excel

Education

Sep 2008 → May 2010 BSc (Hons.) Computer Networks, Sheffield Hallam University, Sheffield, England (1:1, First Class Honours)

Jul 2000 → Mar 2001 BSc (Hons.), Computer Science, Mathematics, Physics, French, English Literature, St. Joseph's College of Science and Arts, Bangalore, India (Discontinued)

Training and Qualifications

- · Certified Kubernetes Administrator, Currently Training to Certify
- Docker + Kubernetes Administration, May 2018
- · OpenStack Deployment and Advanced Administration, Feb 2018
- OpenStack Administration, Sep 2017
- · Citrix NetScaler Essentials, Networking and Administration, Jun 2012
- Building Scalable Cisco Internetworks (CCNP BSCI), Feb 2004
- · Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), Mar 2003
- Implementing & Administering a Microsoft Windows 2000 Directory Services Infrastructure, Apr 2003
- Implementing & Administering a Microsoft Windows 2000 Network Infrastructure, Apr 2003

Professional Membership

Jul 2010 → Present The Institution of Engineering and Technology (IET) (Graduate Member)

Dec 2008 → Present British Computer Society (BCS) (Member)

Jan 2008 → May 2012 Microsoft IT Advisory Council (ITAC) (Member)

Spoken Languages

English (Native), Slovak (Basic Vernacular), French (High School)

Hobbies and Interests

Fatherhood ∘ Cycling, Running, Outdoors ∘ Guitar, Music ∘ Raku Community ∘ Raspberry Pi Hacks

Personal Details

Telephone +421 948 140 290 **Email** s.bhooshi@gmail.com

Address Tučkova 9, Ružinov II, Bratislava 82105, Slovakia

Date of birth 08 Jan, 1983 (□)

Nationality British

Online CV □ Developer Story □ PluralSight □ Github □ LinkedIn □ Keybase □ GC3.2

Download

PDF Version shalom bhooshi-cv.pdf